Ajit Vinayak Nimbalkar (1) Featured

Sr. Umbraco Developer seeking assignment in Software Development, Software Application Development, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, Software Design, Software Maintenance, ASP.NET MVC, C#, Umbraco CMS, Azure Chat Bot, SQL Server, WPF, Silverlight



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer Total Experience: 8 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: McCann Erickson Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Current Location: Mumbai Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Information Technology]

Pref. Location: Mumbai, Pune, Navi Mumbai

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Sr. Umbraco Developer, Software Developer, Software Application Development, Software Development, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, Software Design, Software Maintenance, ASP.NET MVC, C#, Umbraco CMS, Azure

Chat Bot, SQL Server, WPF, Silverlight

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

9 + Years of experience in design, development and maintenance web Based applications.

Expertise in ASP.NET MVC, C#, Umbraco CMS, Azure Chat Bot, SQL Server, WPF, Silverlight.

Excellent Analytical, Organizational and Interpersonal skills. Analysis, Design, Development, Programming & unit testing

Work Experience

McCann Erickson as Senior Software Developer Mar 2020 to Sep 2020

McCann Erickson as Senior Software Engineer Mar 2020 to Till Date

Zensar Technologies Ltd as Sr. Software Engineer Sep 2018 to Feb 2020

Project Title Experience Platform Build Team

Team Size

S/W & Tools Visual Studio, .Net Core, JSON, Postman, C#, MVC.

Project Summary:

Part of Experience Platform Build Team. Build Bot solution (Azure chat bot) using MVC & .Net Core.

My Role was to develop the bot from scratch including following tasks.

Create application azure Luis and QNA maker portal.

Add intents, Entities in Luis application.

Also, add a questions and answers in QNA maker applications.

Fetching Data from Azure Luis and QNA makers application.

Getting user's query intent from luis and pass to QNA maker application.

Also, Integrate third party api's like Zoho & servicenow api for user data save.

Integrate bot on Microsoft Teams.

Project Title Experience Platform Build Team

Team Size 2

Sitecore Experience 8.2, Visual Studio, JSON, Postman, Dev Track, C#, Web services, SQL, MVC, JQuery S/W & Tools and CCS3

Project Summary:

Part of Experience Platform Build Team. Build Widgetized solution (Sitecore Widgets - 10) using MVC & Decorator Design

My Role was to develop the site from scratch including following tasks.

Sitecore Views (MVC).

Sitecore Data Template.

Sitecore Data Items.

Page Build Using Sitecore Data template.

Integration with Backend Application.

Responsive Widgets

Project Title AAA (American Arbitration Association) US

Client American Arbitration Association

Team Size 3

S/W & Tools C#, Web services, SQL, ASP.Net, Umbraco CMS 7.7, JavaScript and CCS3.

Project Summary:

American Arbitration Association (AAA) is at a critical juncture with the Normandy application, implemented approximately ten years ago for managing the organization's dispute resolution operations.

Normandy is outdated and does not provide the flexibility required to meet the changing and evolving business needs of AAA. Subsequent to gathering the business requirements.

For the Prism project AAA is seeking technical strength in UMBRACO CMS and other tools, as well as the governance and methodology leadership from an experienced team to deliver the project.

My Role was to develop the site from scratch including following tasks.

Involved in this project specifically about development part and integration part.

Third party Api Integration like Blue Sky API.

Planning & creating Document types. Template, markup integration & macro creation

Analysis of requirements of client and actual implementation of the project

Development of code as per the client requirements.

Unit testing and system integration testing of the developed code.

Providing fixes to the issues identified in testing phase.

Provide production support for the deployed project till it is stabilized

Received client appreciations for the projects.

Trimax It Infrastructure & Services Ltd as Sr. Software Engineer

Sep 2017 to Sep 2018

Project Title Data Center Service Management

Client Trimax(http://dcsm.trimax.in/)

Team Size

S/W & Tools C#.Net, MVC, JavaScript, MS SQL2008.

Project Summary:

DCSM is will manage data center users, user roles, access report etc. of dcsm.

My Role was to develop the site from scratch including following tasks.

Planning & creating structure for project.

Templating, markup integration & logic creation.

Project Title Canara Bank

Canara Bank (http://www.canarabank.com/)

Team Size

S/W & Tools C#.Net, MVC, Umbraco, Razor, MS SQL2008.

Project Summary:

Canara bank is a universal site for Canara bank. Canara bank will manage content, products, policies etc. from a Single Content Management System.

My Role was to develop the site from scratch including following tasks.

Planning & creating Document types

Templating, markup integration & macro creation.

Custom Controllers(Surface controllers) for forms & applications

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Information Technology) from University Mumbai in 2010

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last U	sed	Experience
C#.net,			
MS SQL Server 2008,2012			
Microsoft Visual Studio 2012,2015,2017			
.net Framework			
MVC, C#, Umbraco, Sitecore			
Azure Chat Bot, SQL Server, Wpf			
Silverlight			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Marathi				

Work Authorization

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time